Thank you, hi everyone,
谢谢，大家好，
thanks Alexander for the introduction.
感谢 Alexander 的介绍。
Alright, very excited to talk about this modern era of statistics,
好的，非常高兴谈论这个统计的现代时代，
you, you've heard throughout the lectures,
你在整个讲座中都听到了，
probably a lot about the, you know, deep learning and the technology that enables this,
可能有很多关于深度学习和实现这一点的技术，
but what I want to talk about,
但我想说的是，
I want to say why works, okay,
我想说为什么管用，
so and give you some intuitions
所以给你一些直觉，
about where we are standing in terms of the theoretical analysis of this system,
关于我们在这个系统的理论分析方面所处的位置，
because a lot of people think that machine learning is an ad hoc field
因为很多人认为机器学习是一个特别的领域，
and deep learning is extremely ad hoc,
而深度学习是非常特别的，
this change a couple of hyper parameters and everything starts working,
这里改变了几个超级参数，一切都开始工作，
but that's not actually the case,
但事实并非如此，
so we have some cues,
所以我们有一些线索，
like what's, what's the whole thing is about, okay.
比如整件事是关于什么的，好的。
Alright, so to motivate,
好的，为了激励大家，
I want to tell you about this,
我想告诉你们这个，
I think it's a very common photo these days,
我认为这是一张非常常见的照片，
that you can see that the more doubling law got broken after 2012
你可以看到 2012 年后更多的倍增法则被打破了，
and we got into kind of a new type of models,
我们进入了一种新的模式，
that as we growth in size on the y axis here,
就像我们在 y 轴上增长的这样，
what you see is that,
你看到的就是，
energy consumption of this models, it could be even accuracy,
这个模型的能耗，甚至可能是准确的，
you know, the accuracy of this models or generalization ability of these models goes higher and higher
这个模型的精确度，或者说这些模型的泛化能力越来越高，
as we scale them, okay,
随着我们对增大它们的规模，
and that's the kind of observation that we had so far.
这就是我们到目前为止所观察到的情况。
And that's what I mean by modern era,
这就是我所说的现代，
because we exhaustively increasing their size,
因为我们竭尽全力地增加它们的大小，
as these photo can show you
这些照片可以向你展示，
like some scale of this large language models, that are out there,
这个大型语言模型的一些比例，
you can see that we have models up to 540 billion parameters,
你可以看到我们有高达 5400 亿个参数的模型，
where, you know, it's beyond our understanding how these models perform representation learning.
这些模型如何执行表示学习超出了我们的理解。
And, it's not only in the realm of language modeling,
而且它不仅在语言模型领域，
but it's also across like different fields,
而且也跨不同的领域，
for example, in time series modeling, in medical diagnosis, in financial time series,
例如，在时间序列建模中，在医疗诊断中，在金融时间序列中，
we have new technologies that are getting better and better with size
我们有新技术，这些技术随着规模的增加而变得越来越好，
and this seems to be the case,
这似乎就是这样，
across different data modalities
跨越不同的数据模式，
and perhaps the one that was present before generative modeling we went from in 2014,
也许 2014 年我们在生成式模型之前出现的数据模式，
generative models like that to generative models like this, right,
这样的生成性模型到这样的生成性模型，
so the quality drastically improve,
所以，质量大幅提高，
not only because of the size,
不仅是因为规模，
but also the underlying structures that enabled us to scale this neural networks,
也是因为潜在的结构使我们能够扩展这种神经网络，
because we already knew that,
因为我们已经知道，
if you have to stack two layers of neural networks next to each other,
如果你必须将两层神经网络堆叠在一起，
you have a universal approximator, right,
你就有了一个通用的逼近器，
so then why couldn't we scale it now,
那么，为什么我们现在不能扩大规模呢，
we had to find the right structure in order to do that,
我们必须找到正确的结构为了做到这一点，
for example, diffusion was one of those structures that actually presented.
例如，扩散是那些实际呈现的结构之一。
So it seems like bigger seems better,
所以看起来越大越好，
but why,
但是为什么呢，
okay, let's find out the reason.
好的，让我们来找出原因。
So you all,
所以你们都知道，
I assume that you would all know how to solve these two equations,
我假设你们都知道如何解这两个方程，
so n equations requires n unknown, right,
所以 n 个方程需要 n 个未知数，对吗，
so how many of you,
那么，你们中有多少人，
you know, still how to solve this kind of thing?
还知道如何解决这种事情？
Yeah, I think it's pretty,
是的，我觉得很好，
but then the crazy thing about deep learning is that,
但是，深度学习的疯狂之处在于，
it comes says that,
它说的是，
yeah, make the number of these X and y larger and larger,
是的，使这些 x 和 y 的数目越来越大，
excessively, for these two equations
对于这两个方程式，
and things, things would start, working even better,
事情就会开始，工作得更好，
and what does it mean even better,
更好意味着什么，
when you have two equations and you have a lot of unknowns,
当你有两个方程式，而你有很多未知数，
how does that even make sense.
这怎么说得通。
You know, let's do an analysis and numerical analysis of the dataset,
让我们对数据集进行分析和数值分析，
you, you all seen this dataset before,
你们以前都看过这个数据集，
it's a handed, handed digit
它是手写的数字，
and as you like, it has 60k points,
它有 60k 个点，
it has them of 28x28 great scale images,
它有 28x28 大比例的图像，
and in today's models,
在今天的模型中，
they have millions of parameters to model 60k images,
它们有数百万个参数来模拟 6 万张图像，
so the performance on this dataset actually keeps improving
所以，这个数据集的性能一直在提高，
as we scale the neural networks,
随着我们扩展神经网络，
and how does this make sense,
这有什么意义呢，
like there is the information basically that you're learning from 60 image 60k images
比如，你从 60k 图像学到的信息，
with millions of data parameters,
使用数百万个数据参数，
what are we learning?
我们学到了什么？
Now, we know that generalization error or test error has this kind of proportion from the theory,
现在，我们从理论上知道，泛化误差或测试误差有这样的比例关系，
that, it's proportional to the number of parameters of the system
它与系统参数个数成正比，
over the square root of number of parameters of the system over the dataset size,
与系统参数个数在数据集大小上的平方根成正比，
that means if I increase the number of parameters of the system,
这意味着如果我增加系统的参数数量，
then I would expect at some point that generalization or the error was high,
那么我预计在某个点上，泛化或误差会很高，
then why is it that we make them larger and larger, but they work?
那么，为什么我们让它们变得越来越大，但它们起作用了呢。
In case of ImageNet and other large scale dataset,
在 ImageNet 或其他大规模数据集的情况下，
a very common machine learning,
非常常见的机器学习，
we have like 1.4M images,
我们大概有 140 万张图像，
of 256x256x3,
尺寸为 256x256x3 ，
and then you have models with hundreds of millions of parameters,
这些模型有数亿个参数，
that you fit this 1.4M images.
可以匹配这 140 万张图像。
In NLP, as we showed before,
在 NLP 中，正如我们之前所展示的，
we have datapoints of few billions
我们有几十亿的数据点，
and then models with hundred billions.
然后是千亿的模型。
And then, perhaps like the best, my favorite kind of illustration
然后，也许是最好的，我最喜欢的示例，
of this size improving performance in this generative AI,
在生成式 AI 中这个尺寸提高性能，
when you have a prompt,
当你有提示时，
this is like a generative AI that receives text input and generates output images,
这就像是生成式 AI 接收文本输入并输出图像，
so the prompt or the input to this system was
所以这个系统的提示或输入是，
a portrait photo of a kangaroo
一张袋鼠的肖像照片，
wearing an orange hoodie and blue sunglasses,
穿着橙色的连帽衫和蓝色的太阳镜，
standing on the grass in front of the Sydney Opera House,
站在悉尼歌剧院前的草地上，
holding a sign on the chest, that says welcome friends.
胸前举着一个牌子，上面写着欢迎朋友。
And as we see,
正如我们所看到的，
that on the top of each image,
在每一张图像的顶部，
we have the size of the model,
我们有模型的大小，
and as we improve the quality of the, the size of the models,
随着我们改善模型的大小，
the quality improves,
质量也会提高，
and we're getting closer and closer to that description that we provided,
我们越来越接近我们提供的描述，
as an input to the system, right,
作为系统的输入，
like the first image actually 350,
比如第一张图片 350 ，
it's still like, has all the components of that input,
它仍然拥有输入的所有组件，
but it's not as good as the last one, right,
但它没有最后一张好，
it misses on a couple of things.
它遗漏了几件事。
Alright, so this happens,
好的，这发生了，
and let's now figure out a way to explain this.
现在让我们找出一种方法来解释这个。
Okay, how many of you have heard about a phenomenon called double descent?
好的，你们中有多少人听说过一种叫做双重下降的现象？
One, two.
一、二。
All right, so,
好的，那么，
all right, so this is not a learning curve first,
好的，所以首先这不是一个学习曲线，
x axis shows the model size,
x 轴显示模型大小，
you have an image classification problem CIFAR-10, you know,
你有一个图像分类问题 CIFAR-10 ，
and these are ten classes, you want to classify these images
这是你希望对这些图像进行分类的十个种类，
and now on the x axis,
现在在 x 轴上，
you are increasing the size of the networks,
你增加网络的大小，
and on the y axis, we see the test error.
在 y 轴上，我们可以看到测试误差。
Okay, let's just concentrate on the,
好的，让我们把注意力集中在，
on the purple side of the basically process,
在基本过程的紫色一侧，
because that's at the end of the training process,
因为这是在训练过程的末尾，
if you're looking at the test error at the end of the process.
如果你查看在过程的末尾的测试错误。
So classical statistics was telling us that,
经典统计学告诉我们，
as you improve, as you increase the size of neural networks up to a certain point,
随着你的改进，当你把神经网络的规模增加到某个点，
you find a nominal point,
你会发现一个标称的点，
where the performance of model the generalization that you have is optimal,
模型的性能，你所拥有的泛化是最佳的，
and from that moment on,
从那一刻起，
if you increase the size of the network, you're overfitting,
如果你增加网络的规模，你就过拟合了，
what that means,
这意味着什么，
that means like the the kind of accuracy,
这意味着精确度，
basically that bell, the first bell shape that starts going up,
第一个钟型开始上升，
as you see, that part was going
正如你所看到的，这个部分，
and, and the project, they projected that that thing is going to go up
他们预测那个东西会上升，
as we actually scale the models,
当我们缩放模型时，
but then the phenomenon that we observed is that,
但我们观察到的现象是，
there is a second descent as we scale the size,
随着我们对规模的扩大，存在第二次下降，
so this is called a double descent phenomenon,
所以这被称为双下降现象，
so first descent we knew already,
我们已经知道的第一次下降，
in the modern era, we figured out that,
在现代，我们计算出，
as we scale this neural networks, the size of the models
当我们扩展这个神经网络，模型的大小，
and this is this has been observed across many different architectures,
这是在许多不同的体系结构中观察到的，
okay, so as we scale, it could be a resonate architecture,
好的，随着我们的扩展，它可以是一个共振架构，
it could be a convolution on neural network,
它可以是神经网络上的卷积，
it could be an LSTM or multiay perceptor or whatever they do,
它可以是 LSTM 或多路感知器或任何其他的，
you know, but as we increase the size,
但随着我们增加尺寸，
that's the kind of phenomena that we see.
这就是我们看到的那种现象。
Now, let me make it a little bit easy, easier to understand,
现在，让我让它变得简单一点，
this was classical statistics in terms of accuracy, now,
精确度而言，这是经典的统计数据，
in the previous one, we were seeing errors,
在前一个中，我们看到的是错误，
now we see accuracy,
现在我们看到的是准确性，
we go high up to a certain point
我们上升到某个点，
and then as we increase the size of the models,
然后随着我们增加模型的大小，
we start overfing,
我们开始过拟合，
now, up to a certain point,
现在，上升到某个点，
now, if you have,
如果你有，
the new kind of experimental results showed that,
新的实验结果表明，
that's actually the case,
这是这样的情况，
where up to a certain point, we go up
上升到某个点，我们上升，
and then again there is an improvement in performance,
然后又有了性能的改善，
this regime is called all over parameterization regime,
这个机制被称为全参数机制，
I'll tell you more,
我会告诉你更多，
and I give you more substance,
我会给你更多的实质内容，
why we call them overparameterized, overparameterization regime,
为什么我们把它们称为过度参数化机制，
should be pretty obvious,
这应该是非常明显的，
but, I put it in the theoretical and the technical kind of language of machine learning.
但是，我把它放在机器学习语言的理论和技术方面。
Alright, so one of the things that we can observe from this image is that,
好的，我们可以从这张图中观察到的一件事是，
the accuracy at the very end of this overparametriization regime is see that,
在这个过度参数化的过程中，最后的精度是，
it's slightly better than the first accuracy that you get from a model that is reasonably sized, okay,
它比你从一个合理大小的模型得到的第一个精度略好，
it's not that much better the accuracy,
精度也好不到哪里去，
but then the discovery of deep learning was that,
但深度学习的发现是，
when we're in the overparameterization regime,
当我们处于过度参数化的机制时，
we get a new type of behavior starts emerging,
我们会得到一种新类型的行为开始出现，
what kind of behavior,
什么样的行为，
the characteristics that emerge in that overparameterization regime
过度参数化制度中出现的特征，
is something that I'm going to talk about next.
是我接下来要谈的。
So one of the things is,
所以其中一件事是，
as we go larger and larger in networks sizes,
随着我们的网络规模越来越大，
they learn concepts that they can pass on to different tasks,
它们会学习可以传递给不同任务的概念，
that means they can generalize across different tasks,
这意味着它们可以在不同的任务中泛化，
that means those concepts that they learn,
这意味着它们学到的那些概念，
they can be transferred to actually perform more tasks,
它们可以被转移到执行更多的任务，
not even a single task that they have been trained on.
甚至不是它们接受过训练的单一任务，
Okay, so,
好的，所以，
it seems like you're giving them more ability to generalize
似乎你给了它们更多的泛化能力，
and getting closer to those kind of kind of general representation of AI,
并越来越接近那种 AI 的一般表现形式，
I'm afraid to say AI yet, okay,
我现在还不敢说 AI ，
but yeah, but that's the kind of thing that we observe,
但这是我们观察的那种事情，
the kind of concepts that they learn,
它们学习的那种概念，
they are being able to perform across different tasks, across different domains,
它们能够跨不同领域执行不同的任务，
they get better and better.
它们变得越来越好。
Another observation that we had is that,
我们得到的另一个观察结果是，
the scale improves robustness,
规模提高了稳健性，
What does it mean for a deep learning model to be robust,
深度学习模型的健壮意味着什么，
that means if I change the input a little bit,
这意味着，如果我在输出有噪声的情况下，
[per] bit with noise,
[每一位]都有噪声，
on the output, it doesn't completely go crash,
在输出，它不会完全崩溃，
so the change of the input is proportional to the output changes,
所以，投入的变化与产出的变化成正比，
so robust means that,
所以健壮性意味着，
you are being being able to control the error and the output,
你能够控制误差和输出，
if you have a little bit of error or deviation of the input.
如果输入有一点误差或偏差。
So this curve actually shows that,
所以这条曲线显示了，
has been scaled these neural networks,
这些神经网络的规模，
we see that the size of, the, the robust actually improve.
我们看到大小，健壮性提高了。
Okay, I'm gonna talk about this in much more detail in,
好的，我将更详细地讨论这一点，
because that's the part where we have the theory for,
因为这是我们用来阐述理论的部分，
from the deep learning perspective.
从深度学习的角度。
Now, not everything improves by, by growing in size,
并不是所有的东西都随着大小的增长而提高，
for example, the problems of bias and accountability
例如，偏见和问责的问题，
and and minor accuracy on minor minority samples,
以及对少数族裔样本的微小准确性的问题，
as we scale, they get worsen.
当我们扩大规模时，它们会变得更糟。
So that's we have evidence for those kind of cases as well,
这就是我们对这类情况的证据，
so you need to be careful,
所以，你需要小心，
when you are deploying this in our society.
当你在我们的社会中部署这一技术时。
Now, another very important part of intelligence, which is reasoning,
智能的另一个非常重要的部分是推理，
the ability to logically talk about kind of different phenomena is basically reasoning
逻辑地讨论不同现象的能力就是推理，
and, and reasoning is basically stays unchanged,
推理基本上是不变的。
if you just scale a model,
如果你只是缩放一个模型，
unless you provide the system with a simulation engine,
除非你给系统提供一个模拟引擎，
let's say you want to do physical reasoning,
比如说你想做物理推理，
say there are two cubes,
假设有两个立方体，
they're both moving in x, on x axis,
它们都在 x 轴上移动，
one of them is faster than the other one,
其中一个比另一个更快，
so one thing that you have as a human being in your head is a simulation engine,
所以你作为一个人在你的大脑里有一个模拟引擎，
that you can basically simulate that kind of reality,
你可以模拟那种现实，
so if you provide that kind of reality to a language model,
所以，如果你为语言模型提供这种现实，
the results of that simulation to language model,
模拟的结果给那个语言模型，
you, you would see again increasing reasoning,
你会看到推理再次增加，
so that part is also extremely important.
所以这一部分也是非常重要的。
Now, the part that we are,
现在，我们的部分就像，
like all these results that I'm showing here,
我在这里展示的所有这些结果，
they are very experimental,
它们都是非常实验性的，
so there has been like a large corporations involved
有一家大公司参与，
to actually perform this kind of analysis
实际执行这种分析，
to actually to see the behavior of this large models,
以看到这些大型模型的行为，
but do we have an actual theory,
但是，我们有没有一个实际的理论，
that fundamentally is true about this models or this behavior that we see,
对于我们所看到的这个模型或这个行为，从根本上是正确的，
let me focus on the robustness.
让我把重点放在健壮性上。
This is from, this kind of graph is from Alexander Madry group from here, MIT,
这个图表来自 MIT Alexander Madry 小组，
where they are studying robustness in neural network,
他们研究神经网络的稳健性，
what they do,
他们的所做的，
I mean, it doesn't matter what, what the three lines are,
我的意思是，不管这三条线是什么，
what they do, they try to attack the input images,
他们所做的，他们试图攻击输入图像，
and then compute the accuracy of models,
然后计算模型的精度，
as we scale, again on the x axis, we see the scale and accuracy
再次，我们在 x 轴上看到规模和精度，
as we start increasing the capacity of the networks,
随着我们增加网络容量，
in image classification and classification here,
在这里图像分类中，
we see that there's a jump in robustness,
我们看到了健壮性的跃升，
that means the attacks that they were doing or perturbing the input images
这意味着他们进行的攻击或干扰输入图像，
with something called an attack is called Projected Gradient Descent,
使用被称为投影梯度下降的攻击，
it was basically, like you,
这就像你，
you got into a really good accuracy
你就会得到非常好的精确度，
after you actually increase the size of the network up to a certain point
当你将网络的规模增加到一定程度后，
and there was this transition, there was a shift in, in, in performance,
然后就会有一个性能的转变，
and that has been confirmed, as I said, by experiments
正如我所说的，这一点已经通过实验得到了证实，
and we said, alright, so scale,
我们说，好的，
the conclusions of those kind of results was that scale improves robustness.
这些结果的结论是，规模提高了稳健性。
But then, and the best paper award
但是后来，获得最佳论文奖的，
at the the Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems 2021,
在神经信息处理系统 2021 会议上，
came and said scale is a law of robustness.
出来说，规模是稳健性的法则。
Okay, what that means,
好的，这意味着什么，
okay, that means like,
好的，这意味着，
let's formulate how scale is basically contributing to robustness.
让我们来阐明，规模是如何从根本上促进稳健性的。
So, I'm gonna talk a little bit more technical about this thing,
所以，关于这件事，我会讲一些更技术性的东西，
hopefully you can, you can all follow,
希望你们都能跟上，
but you you can ask questions,
但你们可以问问题，
Like even now, if you have questions,
即使是现在，如果你有问题，
let me just finish this one and then we'll take some questions.
让我先说完这个，然后我们再回答一些问题。
So let's say fix any reasonable, reasonable function,
所以我们假设修正任何合理的函数，
what is a reasonable function,
什么是合理的函数，
is basically a function that has a smooth behavior,
基本上是一个具有平滑的函数，
like, like a sigmoid function, okay,
比如一个 sigmoid 函数，
that's a very reasonable function, okay,
这是一个非常合理的函数，
a crazy function would be like if you have like jumps across like different modes,
一个疯狂的函数就像你有一个像不同模式的跳跃，
you know, like you have a reasonable function, okay,
你有一个合理的函数，
and it basically, it has, it's parameterized, okay,
它是参数化的，
like a sigmoid function,
就像一个 sigmoid 函数，
that you can parameterize it
你可以对它进行参数化，
and then it's polyized like it has also reasonable size in parameters,
然后它被多极化，就像它在参数中也有合理的大小一样，
and it's not a Kolmogorov-Arnold type network,
它不是 Kolmogorov-Arnold 类型的网络，
what does that mean,
那是什么意思，
that means,
它的意思是，
I'm showing you a representation that was discovered by Arnold and, and, and Kolmogorov,
我给你看的是 Arnold 和 Kolmogorov 发现的描述，
that shows that, there are,
这表明，
this, this decomposition that we see can approximate any continuous function, multivariate continuous function.
我们看到的这种分解可以逼近任何连续函数，多元连续函数。
Okay, so these are basically two non linearities
好的，这是两个非线性函数，
and the sum operator is basically applying, joining the, the, the inner kind of processes,
加法运算符应用，加入内部的过程，
but one problem with this kind of functions is that,
但是这种函数的一个问题是，
they are not as smooth and as [] actually mention,
它们不平滑，像[]提到的，
they show wild behavior,
它们表现出狂野的行为，
they could be anything,
它们可能是任何东西，
the function in inner function could be anything,
内部函数中的函数可以是任何东西，
so let's, let's rule out those kind of functions,
所以让我们排除这种函数，
let's talk about only neural networks,
让我们只讨论神经网络，
okay, like very reasonable functions and really function as well.
好的，非常合理的函数和真正的函数。
Now let's sample n data points for the case of m data set,
现在，我们对 m 个数据集的情况进行采样 n 个数据点，
you have 60k data points, truly high dimensional,
你有 60 万个数据点，真正的高维，
I mean m is like 28x28x1,
我的意思是28乘以28乘以1，所以它就像728，对吗？所以不是那样的。
so it's like 728 right,
所以是 728(784) ，
so it's not that truly high dimensional,
所以，它不是那么真的高维，
but let's say ImageNet is 256x256x3,
但是 ImageNet 是 256x256x3 ，
so truly high dimensional,
所以是真正的高维，
and then add label noise,
然后添加标签噪音，
why, Why do we want to add noise to the labels,
为什么我们要在标签上添加噪音，
what does that mean it,
那是什么意思，
that means we want to make the problem harder for the neural network,
这意味着我们想要让神经网络的问题变得更加困难，
that means it should not be the mapping between the input, high dimensional input than the output classes,
这意味着它不应该是高维输入对比输出类，
should not be trivial, okay,
不应该是微不足道的，
so we add noise, a little bit of label noise
所以我们加上一些噪音，一点的标签噪音，
to basically create this, you know, a complex problem,
就产生了一个复杂的问题，
okay, so that means like if you have all, all your labels are random,
好的，这意味着如果你拥有，所有的标签都是随机的，
the problem is really complex, right,
这个问题真的很复杂，
so you want to add a little bit of random noise as well.
所以，你想添加一点随机噪声。
And then then, to memorize this dataset,
然后，为了记住这个数据集，
what does memorization mean,
记忆意味着什么，
that means, if I have a function
这意味着，如果我有一个函数，
and I'm fitting a parametric model,
我在拟合一个参数模型，
like a neural network to it,
比如一个神经网络，
I want to be completely fitting every single data point, okay, during training,
我想要在训练中完全拟合每一个数据点，
that means I want to achieve a zero loss on my training set, okay,
这意味着我想在我的训练中实现零损失，
that means like memorizing,
这意味着就像记忆一样，
so definition of memorization during learning.
所以在学习过程中记忆的定义。
Now optimize the training error below the noise level
现在，将训练误差优化到低于噪声水平，
and below the noise level, what does that mean,
低于噪声水平，那是什么意思，
again, that's like another definition that you guys have to know is,
同样，你们必须知道的另一个定义是，
as I said, we want to complicate the process,
就像我说的，我们想要使这个过程复杂化，
so that it's not a trivial mapping,
这样它就不是一个微不足道的映射，
so you add that noise
所以你加上噪音，
and then when your accuracy is a little bit higher than the amount of noise that you injected,
然后当你的准确率比你注入的噪声量高一点时，
for example, for the m, basically the hard part of the training of the m dataset,
例如，对于 m ，它是 m 数据集训练的难点部分，
let's say if you,
我们假设你，
all kind of machine learning models can get up to 92% 91% accuracy on the m dataset,
所有类型的机器学习模型都可以在 m 数据集上达到 92% 91% 的准确率，
but then, what's the hard part,
但是，最难的是什么，
the hard part of it is the last 2%-5% to reach the hundred percent,
最难的是最后 2%-5% 才能达到百分之百，
so that's the hard part,
这就是最难的部分，
that's what we call below the noise level, okay,
这就是我们所说的低于噪音水平，
that means if we can learn this process really like with really good accuracy.
这意味着，如果我们能够非常准确地了解这个过程。
Now, and to do this robustly in the sense of Lipschitz,
现在，要在 Lipschitz 条件下做到这种健壮性，
who knows what is the Lipschitz function,
谁知道什么是 Lipschitz 函数，
five, six, okay,
五，六，好的，
alright, so Lipschitz,
好的，所以 Lipschitz ，
so good, that I put this in here,
好的，我把这个放在这里，
so, so as I said,
所以，就像我说的，
look, so your moving your, your input ε,
你移动你的输入 ε ，
okay, a little bit of perturbation at the input of a function,
好的，在函数输入上有一点微扰，
then, if the output is also moving with ε
然后，如果输出也是以 ε 移动，
or proportional linearly proportional to that ε,
或与 ε 成正比的方式移动，
that means this function is Lipschitz,
那就意味着这个函数是 Lipschitz 的，
so you have a controlled kind of process,
所以你有一种受控的过程，
changing the input do not dramatically change the output of a function,
更改输入不会显著更改函数的输出，
that's called the Lipschitz function.
这就是所谓的 Lipschitz 函数。
Now, yeah, so you memorize the data,
现在，是的，所以你记住了这些数据，
and you want to do this memorization robustly,
你想要健壮地记忆，
so if you want to do that,
所以，如果你想这样做，
it is necessary is absolutely necessary to parameterize your neural network at least equal to n,
对你的神经网络进行参数化至少等于 n 是绝对必要的，
n is basically the dimensionality of your dataset,
n 是你的数据集的维度，
which is 60k times d,
也就是 60k 乘以 d ，
d is the dimensionality of your of every input sample,
d 是你的每个输入的维度，
let's say if your input is m dataset,
假设你的输入是一个 m 数据集，
I mean I'm gonna give you an example later on,
我的意思是，稍后我会给你一个例子，
but, let's say the input is 728, in the order of [10 to the power 3],
但是，假设输入是 728 ， [10 的 3 次方]，
and the number of dataset is 60k, right,
而数据集的数量是 60K ，
then the minimum size of m dataset has to be [10 to the power 8],
然后， m 数据集的最小大小必须是 [10 的 8 次方]，
that would be the size of the neural network model [10 to the power 9],
神经网络模型大小是 [10 的 9 次方]，
to robustly learn m dataset,
来健壮地学习 m 数据集，
that's a huge neural network,
这是一个巨大的神经网络，
but this is one of the fundamental explanations, very recent,
但这是我们最近的基本解释之一，
that we have about the theory of deep learning
关于深度学习理论，
and why is it called dramatic overparamatization,
为什么它被称为戏剧性的超越参数化，
because intuitively, as we showed before,
因为直观地说，就像我们之前展示的那样，
memorizing n data points would require n parameters
记忆 n 个数据点需要 n 个参数，
and we had [] and [],
我们有 [] 和 []，
they were showing that two, two layer neural network with threshold activation function,
他们展示了两个具有阈值激活函数的两层神经网络，
they showed it in 1988,
他们在 1988 年证明，
that you would need p the number of parameters you would need
你需要的参数的数量 p ，
almost equivalent order of number of dataset, data points that you have,
几乎等同于你拥有的数据集，数据点的数量的数量级，
that would actually would be enough theoretically,
从理论上讲，这将是足够的，
and then they showed it recently for the radio networks,
然后他们最近在 ReLU 网上展示了这一点，
and we even have that in the Neural Tangent Kernels,
我们甚至在神经正切核中也有这一点，
so how many of you are familiar with Neural Tangent Kernels,
那么，你们当中有多少人熟悉神经正切核，
three out of three, at one, two.
三局三胜，一，二。
Yeah, so Neural Tangent Kernels is that,
是的，所以神经正切核是，
so, imagine the process of training and neural network with gradium descent,
所以，想象一下梯度下降的训练和神经网络的过程，
the whole process from beginning of training to the end of training is a dynamical process,
从训练开始到训练结束的整个过程是一个动态的过程，
that means you're updating the weights of the system as you go further,
这意味着，随着你更进一步，你将更新系统的权重，
given a dataset, given a neural network, and given the parameters of your optimizer,
给定一个数据集，给定一个神经网络以及给定优化器的参数的情况下，
you can this learning dynamics can be converge,
这种学习动态可以收敛，
if I can actually be modeled by a dynamical process,
如果我可以用一个动态过程来建模，
my differential equation that explains how the updates of gradient descent of a neural network would work.
我的微分方程式解释了神经网络的梯度下降更新是如何工作的。
Now, if I increase the size of the neural network to infinite width,
现在，如果我将神经网络的大小增加到无限宽，
I increase the size of the neural network to infinite width,
我增加神经网络到无限宽，
then this dynamic of learning has a close form solution,
然后这种动态学习就有了一个封闭形式的解，
that means it has actually a solution,
这意味着它实际上有一个解，
which is a kernel method,
这是一种核心方法，
so basically you will end up having a kernel,
所以从根本上说，你最终将拥有一个内核，
and that kernel explains the entire behavior and dynamics of your learning process in the infinite way,
这个核心以无限的方式解释了你学习过程的整个行为和动态，
this is called the Neural Tangent Kernel theory
这就是神经正切核理论，
and we have a PHD student, actually sitting over there,
我们有一个博士生坐在那里，
Noel Loo, that is focusing on that,
Noel Loo ，他正在专注于这个问题，
and this is actually his PHD topic that he's working on in Daniela lab.
这是他正在研究的博士生话题，在 Daniela 实验室。
Okay, so now let's let's move from this ah theory
好的，现在让我们离开这个理论，
and let's, let's give an example,
让我们举一个例子，
so we have the MNIST dataset,
所以我们有 MNIST 数据集，
it has around 10 to the power 5 number of parameters,
它有大约 10 的 5 次方的参数，
the dimensionality of each data point is 10 to power 3,
每个数据点的维度是 10 的 3 次方，
728 just the scale,
728 是它的尺寸，
and then we saw the transition in the kind of robustness,
然后我们看到了一种健壮性的转变，
that is like, at least you need to have 10 to power 6 parameters
至少你需要有 10 的 6 次方个参数，
to robustly fit the MNIST dataset.
才能稳健地拟合 MNIST 数据集。
But then there are a couple of notes that we want to have,
但是还有几个点是我们想要的，
the notion of robustness in the in the theory paper
理论论文中的稳健性概念
was a little bit different than the notion of robustness at Lipschitz,
与 Lipschitz 中的概念略有不同，
that we showed in the, in the theory of law robustness,
那个我们在健壮性法则中展示的，
and then another point is that,
然后另一点是，
the law seems to be contradicted,
法则似乎是矛盾的，
because if you multiply,
因为如果你乘以，
we just said the law is like you know n times d, right,
我们刚才说的法则就是 n 乘以 d ，
like that's the minimum number of samples that you can, you have the transition,
这是你所能得到的最小样本数，你可以转换，
so, but here if you do that 10 times,
但是，如果你做 10 乘以，
10 to power 5 times 10 to power 3 is 10 to power 8
10 的 5 次方乘以 10 的 3 次方是 10 的 8 次方，
and it's much larger than that 10 to power 6 that was observed in reality.
这比在现实中观察到的 10 的 6 次方要大得多。
But, one of the things that you have to also notice is that,
但是，你还必须注意的一件事是，
there's something about datasets is called effective dimensionality,
关于数据集，有一种东西被称为有效维度，
and effective dimensionality means that,
有效维度意味着，
when I show you an image,
当我向你们展示一幅图像时，
there are principal components of an image,
图像的主要组成部分，
so finding the principal components of an image,
所以，找出图像的主要成分，
that how small that image, what's the information,
即图像有多小，信息是什么，
the information is not the same size as the pixel itself,
信息与像素本身的大小不同，
the information is much smaller,
信息要小得多，
so the effective dimensionality of,
所以，有效维度是，
it's hard to actually determine what's the effective dimensionality of a given dataset,
很难确定给定数据集的有效维度是多少，
but still, for the MNIST dataset,
但对于 MNIST 数据集，
it's 10 to the power 1
它是 10 的 1 次方，
and now we have 10 to power 5 in
现在我们有 10 的 5 次方，
and if the effective dimensionality is basically 10 to power 1,
如果有效维度基本上是 10 的 1 次方，
then you would have basically the same,
那么你会得到相同的，
you can confirm with experiments the theoretical results that was observed with the law of robustness.
你可以用实验来证实用稳健性法则观察到的理论结果。
Now the noisy labels, as I said,
现在，噪音标签，正如我所说的，
it's basically learning the difficult part of the training,
它是学习训练中困难的部分，
and then, in regard to ImageNet is basically shows the law of robustness predict,
然后，关于 ImageNet 的预测表现出稳健性的法则，
because we haven't yet trained super large networks,
因为我们还没有训练超大型的网络，
it seems like the networks that we have trained so far, they are actually small,
到目前为止，我们训练的网络似乎都很小，
you know, we haven't trained like really large neural networks still,
我们仍然没有训练真正的大型神经网络，
but they have to be on the order of 10 to power 12 or 10 to power 10, you know,
但是它们必须是 10 的 12 次方或 10 的 10 次方数量级，
and this is like the prediction of the law of robustness.
这就是对稳健性法则的预测。
Okay, so now let's get back to this image,
好的，现在让我们回到这张图片上，
so all these networks that I was talking about and law of robustness,
所以我所说的所有这些网络和稳健性法则，
basically in that regime,
基本上在那个机制下，
in that regime, I showed you that we have great generalization,
在那个机制下，我向你展示了我们有很好的普遍性，
we get more robust, probably more robustness,
我们得到更多的健壮性，可能更多的健壮性，
and then reasoning still we have questions about how to achieve it
然后推理我们还有一个问题，那就是如何实现它，
and then bias and fairness, which is very important,
然后是偏见和公平，这是非常重要的，
energy consumption and accountability of the models.
能源消耗和模型的责任。
There is a way,
有一种方法，
and that has been the focus of the research
这是研究的重点，
that we have been doing at Daniela Rus's lab
我们在 Daniela Rus 的实验室所做的，
with Alexander and a couple of other graduate students of ours,
与 Alexander 和我们的其他几名研究生一起，
is to find out how can we get out of that overparameterization regime,
就是找出我们如何在解决超参数机制，
while addressing all these [social technical] challenges.
解决所有这些[社会技术]挑战。
And how we did that,
我们是如何做到这一点的，
we went back to source,
我们回到了源头，
basically, we looked into brains, okay,
我们调查了大脑，
we looked into how we can get inspiration from brains
我们研究了如何从大脑中获得灵感，
to improve over architectural biases that we have in neural networks
以改进我们在神经网络中的架构偏见，
in order to break the law of robustness.
以打破健壮性法则。
Now and then we we invented something called Liquid Neural Networks,
然后我们发明了一种叫做液态神经网络的东西，
the direct inspiration from how neurons and synapses interact with each other in the brain, okay,
它的直接灵感来自于神经元和突触在大脑中相互作用的方式，
that's how, we, we started our focus
这就是我们开始我们的重点，
and the second half of my talk,
在我演讲的后半部分，
I'm just gonna talk about Liquid Neural Networks and their implications in this realm of modern era of statistics.
我只想谈谈液态神经网络及其在现代统计学领域的意义。
So, as I said, we started with nervous systems,
所以，就像我说的，我们从神经系统开始，
then, in order to understand their assistance,
然后，为了了解他们的帮助，
you want to go down and you you can look into neural circuits,
你想要下去，你可以研究神经回路，
neural circuits are circuits that are composed of neurons,
神经回路是由神经元组成的回路，
then they can get sensory inputs and generate some, some sort of outputs, [motor] outputs,
然后它们可以获得感觉输入并生成一些类型的输出，
and then we went even deeper than that
然后我们进行了更深入的研究，
and we looked into how neurons, individual neurons, communicate with each other to cells,
我们研究了单个神经元，是如何相互交流，
receiving information between each other,
接收彼此之间的信息的，
and then we arrived at an equation that or a formulation
然后我们得出了一个方程或公式，
for the interaction of neurons and synapses,
对于神经元和突触相互作用，
that is abstract enough, so that we can perform computation, efficient computation,
它足够抽象，这样我们就可以进行计算，高效的计算，
but at the same time has more details of how the actual computation happens in, in, in brains,
但同时也有更多关于计算如何在大脑中发生的细节，
and not just the threshold or activate, very kind of the function that we see.
而不仅仅是门槛或激活，我们看到的那种函数。
So let's get more deeper into that.
所以，让我们更深入地了解这个。
And we showed that,
我们展示了，
if you really get into more biologically plausible representation of neural networks,
如果你真的对神经网络进行了更多生物学上可信的表示，
you can gain more expressivity,
你就可以获得更多的表现力，
you can handle memory in a much more natural way,
你可以用一种更自然的方式来处理记忆，
you gain some properties, such as causality
你得到了一些性质，比如因果关系，
and which was basically something that we haven't discussed
这是我们没有讨论过的，
and what's the cause and effect of task,
任务的因果关系是什么，
can we actually learn that,
我们真的能学到这些吗，
you can get to robustness
你可以达到健壮性，
and you don't need to be crazy like large,
你不需要像大的一样疯狂，
the out of the that regime,
在那个机制之外，
you can perform a generative modeling,
你可以执行一个生成性模型，
which was, what I described as before
这是我之前描述的，
and you can even do extrapolation,
你甚至可以进行推断，
that means you can,
这意味着你可以，
you can even go beyond the the kind of data that you have been trained on,
你甚至可以超越你所接受过训练的那种数据，
that means you can, you can go out of distribution,
这意味着你可以跳出分布，
that something that we couldn't do
我们之前不能做的事情，
and like the, the area that we were focused on was robotics, real world,
我们关注的领域是机器人，现实世界，
you know like we call it mixed horizon decision making
比如我们所说的混合视野决策，
and means if you have a robot interacting in the environment in a real setting,
意思是如果你有一个机器人在一个真实的环境中交互，
now how to bring this kind of networks inside real world,
现在如何将这种网络带入现实世界，
and that's the focus of our research.
这也是我们研究的重点。
Yeah, so, what are the building blocks of this type of neural networks,
是的，所以，这种类型的神经网络的基础是什么，
I said the building blocks are basically interaction of two neurons or two cells with each other,
我说的基础是两个神经元或两个细胞之间的相互作用，
one of some observation about this process.
对这一过程的一些观察。
The first observation is that,
第一个观察是，
the kind of interaction between two neurons in the brain is a continuous time process,
大脑中两个神经元之间的相互作用是一个连续的时间过程，
so that's something to account for,
所以这是需要解释的，
so we're not talking about discrete processes.
所以我们不是在谈论离散过程。
Another thing is that synaptic release,
另一件事是突触释放，
right now in neural networks,
现在在神经网络种，
when you connect to nodes with each other,
当你相互连接节点时，
you connect them with a scalar weight, right,
你用标量权重将它们连接起来，
now, what if I tell you that,
现在，如果我告诉你，
when you, when two neurons interact with each other,
当两个神经元相互作用时，
it's not only a scalar weight,
它不是一个标量权重，
but there is actually a probability distribution,
而是一个概率分布，
that how many kind of neurotransmitters generated from one cell
一个细胞产生的多少种神经递质
is going to bind to the channels of the other cell
将结合到另一个细胞的通道上，
and how it can actually activate the other cell,
以及它如何真正激活另一个细胞，
so the communication between the nodes is very sophisticated
所以，节点之间的通信是非常复杂的，
and it's one of the fundamental building blocks of intelligence,
这是智能的基本构建块之一，
which we have actually abstracted way in artificial neural network to a weight, to scale weight.
我们已经在人工神经网络中抽象出标量权重的方式。
Now, another point is that,
现在，另一个点是，
we have massive parallelization and massive recurrence and feedback and memory and sparsity kind of structures in brains,
我们在大脑中有大量的并行化和大量的重复、反馈、记忆和稀疏的那种结构，
and that's something that is missing from,
而这正是我们所缺失的，
not entirely, but, but somehow it's missing from the artificial network,
不是完全的，但一些从人工网络中消失了，
we deviated a little bit.
我们有一点偏离了。
Now what I want to argue is that,
现在我想说的是，
if we incorporate all these building blocks,
如果我们整合所有这些构件，
we might get into better representation,
我们可能会得到更好的表示，
learning more flexible models and robust
学习更灵活的模型和健壮性，
and at the same time be able to interpret those results
同时能够解释这些结果，
and this and for because the first reason,
因为第一个原因，
that the whole process was build on top of continuous time processes,
整个过程是建立在连续时间过程之上的，
let's get get into this continuous time processes,
让我们进入连续时间过程，
where we are in terms of neurural networks, continuous time processes.
就神经网络而言，连续时间过程。
So here I'm showing you an equation,
这里我给你们展示一个方程式，
so f is a neural network,
所以 f 是一个神经网络，
it could be a five layer network, six layer neural network, fully connected,
它可以是一个五层，六层神经网络，完全相连，
but this f that has n layers and width k, and then it has a certain activation function,
但是这个 f 有 n 层，宽度 k ，然后它有一个激活函数，
it has, it's a function that receives input,
它是一个接收输入的函数，
it receives recurrent connections from the other cells,
它接收来自其他细胞的循环连接，
it receives exogenous input as well, like this I,
它也接受外部输入，比如这个 I ，
and it is parameterized by θ,
并且它是由 θ 参数化的，
now this neural network is parameterizing the derivatives of the hidden state and not hidden state itself,
这个神经网络将隐藏状态的导数参数化，而不是隐藏状态本身，
that builds a continuous time neural network,
这建立了一个连续时间的神经网络，
now, if you have a continuous time process,
现在，如果你有一个连续的时间过程，
that means like the updates or the output of a neural network
这意味着神经网络的更新或输出，
is actually generating the updates of your derivative of the hidden state and not hidden state itself,
是生成隐藏状态的导数的更新，而不是隐藏状态本身，
what kind of you can give rise to continuous time dynamics
你可以给出[连续时间动态]，
with neural networks that we haven't explored before.
对于我们以前从未探索过的神经网络。
Now, what does this mean in terms of like neural networks,
那么，对于神经网络，这意味着什么，
let's look at this, this image,
我们来看看这张图片，
how many of you have heard about Residual Networks?
你们当中有多少人听说过残差网络？
Okay, Residual Networks are deep neural networks that have a kind of skip connections, okay,
好的，残差网络是深度神经网络有一种跳过连接，
like from one layer to the other one, you basically skip connections
比如从一层到另一层，你可以跳过连接，
and that skip connection is model by this equation,
跳过连接的模型是这样的，
ht+1 equal to ht plus f of whatever,
ht+1 等于 ht 加上 f 什么，
that ht is basically resembling basically a skip connection.
ht 类似于一种跳过连接。
And now here on the y axis,
现在在 y 轴上，
what we see, we see the depth of neural network
我们看到的是神经网络的深度，
and each dot, each black dot here,
这里的每个黑点，
shows a computation that happened in the system,
显示了系统中发生的计算，
so when you have a neural network that is layer wise,
所以当你有一个神经网络是层级的，
like let's call it layer wise,
我们称之为层级，
because the photos actually showing the layers in the vertical axis,
因为图片显示了垂直轴上的层，
so if you look at the vertical axis,
所以，如果你查看垂直轴，
you see that computation happen at each layer,
你会看到计算发生在每一层，
because as the input is computed from the first layer to the second one
因为输入是从第一层到第二层，
and then the next one, next one,
然后是下一层，下一层，
but if you have a continuous process,
但是如果你有一个连续的过程，
continuous process equivalent to this process,
连续的过程等于这个过程，
you have the ability to compute at an arbitrary point in a vector field,
你有能力在矢量场中的任意点计算，
so if you, if you know what are differential equations
所以如果你知道什么是微分方程，
and how, how do they basically change the entire space into a vector field,
他们如何把整个空间变成一个矢量场，
how can you basically go,
你怎么去，
you know, you, you can do adaptive computation, okay,
你可以做自适应计算，
and that's one of the massive benefits of continuous time processes.
这是连续时间过程的巨大好处之一。
Now, in terms of things that you have seen before,
现在，就你们以前见过的东西来说，
standard recurring neural networks,
标准的递归神经网络，
you had the lecture here,
你在这里上过课，
so a neural network f is basically computes the next step of the hidden state,
所以神经网络 f 计算隐藏状态的下一步，
so, it's a [] kind of process of [] the next step,
所以，它是[]下一步的一种[]过程，
and neural ODE updates the state with a neural network like that,
神经 ODE 通过这样的神经网络来更新状态，
in a continuous time fashion,
以连续时间的方式，
and then there is a better, more stable version of this differential equation,
然后这个微分方程有一个更好，更稳定的版本，
that is called continuous time or CTRNN [recur] networks,
叫做连续时间或 CTRNN 循环网络，
there continuous time recur networks where,
在连续时间循环网络中，
they have a damping factor,
它们有一个衰减因子，
so that differential a linear ODE or differential equation,
所以这个微分是一个线性的 ODE 或微分方程，
that describes basically the dynamics of them, of a neural network,
描述了神经网络的动态性，
hidden state of neural network.
神经网络的隐藏状态。
Now, in terms of what kind of, what kind of, ah, benefits will you get,
现在，在你会获得什么样的好处方面，
let's look at the top one,
让我们看看最上面的图，
these are thestruction plots from data data corresponding on to a spiral dynamics,
这些是从对应于螺旋动力学的数据数据结构图，
if you have a disized neural network,
如果你有一个二维神经网络，
this spiral dynamics is being able to,
这种螺旋动力学能够，
you know, it the, the, the kind of interpolation that you have kind of [edgy],
你有一种[前卫的插补]，
but if you have a continuous time process,
但是如果你有一个连续的时间过程，
it actually can compute very smoothly
它可以非常顺利地计算，
and also it can even generalize to the unseen area of this,
甚至可以推广到这个看不见的区域，
which is the red part of this,
这个的红色部分，
as we see here,
正如我们在这里看到的，
the normal require network misses out on on this kind of spiral dynamics,
正常的需求网络错过了这种螺旋式的动态，
so the continuous time process,
所以在连续的时间过程中，
it is believe that you can get better and better representation only,
它只能相信你能得到越来越好的表现，
but then the problem here is that,
但这里的问题是，
if you, if, if, if you actually bring this models in practice,
如果你真的把这个模型带到实践中，
a simple LST networks better than this type of network,
一个简单的 LSTM 网络比这种类型的网络工作得更好，
so basically you, you can actually outperform everything that we showed here with LSTM network, so far,
所以，到目前为止，你可以使用 LSTM 网络超越我们在这里展示的所有东西，
so what's the point of basically creating such complex architectures and stuff?
那么，创建如此复杂的架构和东西有什么意义？
So this was the place where we thought that the continuous time processes that we bring from nature
这就是我们认为我们从大自然带来的连续时间过程，
can actually help us build better inductive biases.
可以帮助我们建立更好的归纳偏见的地方。
So we introduced a neural network called Liquid Time-Constant networks, on short LTCs,
所以，我们引入了一种名为液态时间常数网络的神经网络，简称 LTC ，
LTCs are constructed by neurons and synapses,
LTC 由神经元和突触构成，
so a neuron model is a continuous process,
神经元模型就是这样一个连续的过程，
like that, it's a differential equation, a linear differential equation,
这是一个线性微分方程，
that receives the synaptic input S,
它接受突触输入 S ，
neurons and synapses,
神经元和突触，
now we have a synapse model S(t) is a function,
现在我们有一个突触模型 S(t) 是一个函数，
that has a neural network multiplied by a term called a difference of potential,
它有一个神经网络乘以一个叫做势差的术语，
that non-linearity resembles the non-linear behavior between the synapses in real kind of neurons,
这种非线性类似于真实神经元中突触之间的非线性行为，
if you have synaptic connections and they are basically designed by non-linearity,
如果你有突触连接，它们是由非线性设计的，
because that's actually the reality of the thing.
因为这是事实。
And then if you, if you plug in this S inside this linear equation,
然后，如果你把这个 S 代入这个线性方程，
you will end up having a differential equation which is looking very sophisticated,
你会得到一个看起来很复杂的微分方程，
but you will see the implications of this differential equation,
但你会看到这个微分方程式的含义，
it has a neural network as a coefficient of x(t),
它有一个神经网络作为 x(t) 的系数，
which is this x(t) here,
就是这里的 x(t) ，
that neural network is input dependent,
这个神经网络是输入依赖的，
That means the inputs to the neural network defines how the behavior of this differential equation is going to be,
这意味着神经网络的输入定义了这个微分方程式的行为，
so it sets the behavior of the differential equation,
所以它设定了微分方程的行为，
in a way that when you're deploying this system on board,
当你在部署这个系统时，
it can be adaptable to inputs,
它可以适应输入，
so this neural network, this system,
所以这个神经网络，这个系统，
if you have it in practice, it's input dependent,
如果你在实践中有它，它是输入依赖的，
and as you change the input as the result of inputs,
当你改变作为输入结果的输入时，
the behavior of this differential equation changes.
这个微分方程式的行为也会改变。
Now, in terms of connectivity structures, it has,
现在，在连接结构方面，
if you look at the range of possible connectivity structures,
如果你看看可能有的连接结构的范围，
that you have in a standard world network,
你在标准世界网络中有的，
you would have sigmoid basically activation functions,
你会有 sigmoid ，激活函数，
you might have reciprocal connections between two notes,
你可能有两个节点之间的相互连接，
you might have external inputs
你可能有外部输入，
and you might have a recurrent connections for a standard neural network.
你可能有一个标准神经网络的循环连接。
Now, for a Liquid neural network,
现在，对于液态神经网络，
instead, each node in the system is a differential equation,
相反，系统中的每个节点都是一个微分方程，
xj and xi, they have dynamics,
xj 和 xi ，它们有动态，
and then they are connected by synapses,
然后它们通过突触联系在一起，
and then there are process, non-linear processes that controls the interaction of synapses,
然后有非线性过程控制突触相互作用，
so now in some sense,
所以现在在某种意义上，
you can think about liquid neural networks as being being processes,
你可以认为液态神经网络是过程，
that have non-linearity of the system of synapses instead of the neurons.
有着突触系统的非线性过程，而不是神经元。
So in neural networks,
所以在神经网络中，
we have the activation functions,
我们有激活函数，
which are the non-linearity of the system,
它们是系统的非线性，
now you can think about non-linearity of the system being on the synapses or the weight of the system.
现在你可以认为系统的非线性作用在突触上，或者系统的权重。
Now, in terms of practice,
现在，就实践而言，
let's look at this application,
让我们来看看这个应用程序，
here, we train an artificial neural network,
我们训练一个人工神经网络，
that can control a car,
它可以控制一辆车，
that can drive the car in this environment
它可以在这种环境下驾驶汽车，
and what we are showing on the sides of this middle image,
我们在这张中间图像的两侧所显示的内容，
is the activity of two neurons,
是两个神经元的活动，
that are inside the standard neural network and a Liquid neural network,
分别是标准神经网络和液态神经网络，
on the x axis, we see the time constant or sensitivity of the behavior of the output behavior,
在 x 轴上，我们看到的是时间常数或敏感的输出行为，
basically controlling the vehicles steering angle,
控制着车辆的转向角度，
the sensitivity of that control on the x axis
x 轴上控制的灵敏度，
and on the y axis, we see the steering angle,
在 y 轴上，我们可以看到转向角，
the color also represents the output,
颜色还表示输出，
which is mapping between the steering angle and the output of the neural network.
转向角和神经网络输出之间的映射输出。
Okay, so now as we see,
好的，现在我们看到，
we added with liquid neural network,
我们添加了液态神经网络，
we have an additional degree of freedom,
我们有一个额外的自由度，
that that these networks can set its sensitivity,
这些网络可以设置它的敏感度，
a liquid neural network,
一个液态神经网络，
depending on whether we're turning, whether we are going straight,
取决于我们是不是转弯，是不是直走，
if you're going straight, the, the time constant, you want to be more cautious,
如果你是直走，时间常数要比较谨慎，
when you taking turns, right,
当你转弯的时候，
so your neural network,
所以你的神经网络，
you want to, you want to to be faster
你想要更快，
to be able to actually control during those kind of, kind of events,
以便能够在那种事件中进行实际控制，
where you're actually turning,
当你转弯的时候，
so that's the kind of degree that you can add,
这就是你可以添加的程度，
even at the neuronal level for interpreting these systems.
甚至在神经元层面上也可以解释这些系统。
Now, let's look at the case study of liquid neural networks,
现在，让我们来看看液态神经网络的案例研究，
so usually you saw a deep neural network for an autonomous driving application,
通常情况下，你会看到自动驾驶应用程序的深度神经网络，
we have a conv, stack of convolution on networks,
我们在网络上有一个卷积堆栈，
they receive camera inputs
它们接收摄像头的输入，
and they can output the a kind of a steering angle at its output.
并在输出端输出一种转向角。
This kind of neural network,
这种神经网络，
one of the things that we can do,
我们可以做的事情之一，
first of all, they have like a lot of parameters in this system,
首先，它们在这个系统中有很多参数，
what we want to do,
我们要做的是，
we want to take out the fully connected layers of this neural network
我们想去掉这个神经网络的完全连通层，
and replace it with recurrent neural network processes,
用递归神经网络过程来代替它，
one of those recurrent processes that we replace it
我们想取代它的一种递归神经网络过程，
with liquid neural network and the LSTM and the normal continuous time neural networks.
使用液态神经网络， LSTM 和正常的连续时间神经网络。
Now, if I replace this,
现在，如果我替换这个，
I would end up having like four different variants,
我最终会有四个不同的变体，
this four variants,
这四种变体，
one of them is called an NCP,
其中之一被称为 NCP ，
which is a neural circuit policy, that has a four layer architecture,
这是神经回路策略，具有一个四层架构，
each node of this system is defined by an LTC neuron,
这个系统的每个节点都是由一个 LTC 神经元定义的，
that equations that I was showing you,
我刚才展示给你们的方程，
and it is sparsely connected to the other parts of the network.
它与网络的其他部分稀疏地连接在一起。
So we have a sparse neural network architecture here,
所以我们这里有一个稀疏的神经网络结构，
we have then one neural network,
然后我们有一个神经网络，
that has LSTM as the control signal,
它以 LSDM 作为控制信号，
it receives the perception with convolution neural networks.
它通过卷积神经网络接收感知。
And then we have CT-RNNs
然后我们有 CT-RNN ，
and we have a convolutional neural networks,
我们有一个卷积神经网络，
now I want to show you the driving performance of these different types of networks
现在我想向你展示这些不同类型的网络的驾驶性能，
and what kind of characteristics is added to these systems.
以及这些系统增加了什么样的特征。
So first let's look at these dashboard,
首先让我们来看看这些仪表板，
where, where I'm showing you a convolution on neural network,
在那里我向你展示了神经网络的卷积，
followed by fully connected layers,
然后是完全连接的层，
a normal, very standard deep learning system,
一个正常的、非常标准的深度学习系统，
that receives those camera inputs and has learned to control this car,
它接收摄像头输入并已经学会了控制这辆车，
okay, so those camera inputs comes in and the output decisions are basically driving decisions.
好的，这些摄像头的输入和输出决定是驾驶决策。
Now, on the bottom left, what we see,
现在，在左下角，我们所看到的，
we see the decision making process of this system,
我们看到了这个系统的决策过程，
the inputs, if you realize the input has a little bit of noise on top of them,
如果你意识到输入上有一点噪音，
so I added some noise at the input,
我在输入端添加了一些噪声，
so, so that we can see the robustness in decision making of this process.
这样我们就可以看到这个过程决策的健壮性。
And as we see,
正如我们所看到的，
actually there is the, the kind of decision making the brighter regions here
做出决策的较亮区域，
is where the neural network is paying attention,
是神经网络正在关注的，
when it's taking a driving decision.
当它做出驾驶决定的时候。
And we see that, the attention is basically scattered with a little bit of noise on top of the system.
我们看到，注意力基本上分散在系统的顶部，有一点噪音。
Now, if you do the same thing and add noise,
现在，如果你做同样的事情并增加噪声，
we then replace that fully connected layer of neural network with 19 liquid neurons,
我们就用 19 个液态神经元来替换那个完全连接的神经网络层，
you can actually get to a performance of lane keeping on the same environment,
你可以得到相同环境的车道保持的性能，
while having the attention of the system being basically focus on the road horizon,
让系统的注意力集中在道路地平线上，
like the way that we actually drive, right,
就像我们实际驾驶的方式，
so, and the fact that,
所以，事实是，
the parameters that are needed for performing this task,
执行此任务所需的参数，
basically, 19 neurons with a very small convolution on neural network as perception modelule,
19 个神经元，在神经网络上有一个非常小的卷积作为感知模型，
that's the fascinating part,
这是吸引人的部分，
that you get from that inductive bias that we put inside neural networks from brains, okay.
我们从大脑获得的把感应偏见放在神经网络中。
So if you model that,
所以如果你建模，
so you, you have like a set of neurons,
你有一组神经元，
that you can really go through their dynamics,
你可以通过它们的动态，
you can analyze them,
你可以分析它们，
you can understand that process of that system.
你可以理解那个系统的过程。
And you get benefits like real world benefits,
你得到的好处就像现实世界的好处，
for example, if on the x axis,
例如，如果在 x 轴上，
as I increase the noise,
当我增加噪音时，
I increase the noise,
我增加了噪音，
the amount of noise that I add the input,
我增加了输入的噪声量，
and on the y axis, I compute the output,
在 y 轴上我计算了输出，
crashes, number of crashes, that actually happens when the drive,
发生在驾驶过程中，撞车的次数，
when the network wants to drive the car outside,
当网络想要把车开到外面时，
we see that these are the other networks,
我们看到这些是其他网络，
and here we see liquid neural network,
我们在这里看到液态神经网络，
where actually keeps the level extremely low, LTCs.
将水平保持在极低的水平， LTC 。
If you look into the attention map of different, those four different network variants,
如果你看看这四种不同网络变体的关注图，
how do they make driving decisions when they are deployed in the environment,
当它们部署在环境中时，它们是如何做出驾驶决策的，
we see that the consistency of attention is different across different networks,
我们看到，不同网络的注意力一致性是不同的，
while we have a liquid neural network actually maintains its focus,
我们有一个液态神经网络，保持了它的关注点，
and that's one of the nice thing about this,
这是这件事的好处之一，
but then we ask why,
但随后我们会问为什么，
why is it that the liquid neural network can focus on the actual task,
为什么液态神经网络可以专注于实际任务，
which is lane keeping here,
也就是这里的车道保持，
there is no driving and just a simple driving example where you have,
没有驾驶，只有一个简单的驾驶例子，
just, you know, like a road and you want to stay in the road, right.
只有一条路，你想留在路上。
Then,
然后，
now what, as I said,
现在，就像我说的，
like the representation that learned by a liquid neural network is much more causal,
通过液体神经网络学习的表示法更有因果性，
so that means they can,
所以这意味着它们可以，
they can really focus and find out the essence of the task.
它们可以真正集中精力，找出任务的本质。
And then if you look into the machine learning modeling,
然后如果你研究机器学习建模，
statistical modeling is like the least form of causal modeling
统计建模就像是最起码的因果建模，
is basically you just extract,
就是你只是提取，
these are like, these are the taxonomies of the causal models,
这些是因果模型的分类，
you have on the bottom of this axis,
你在轴的底部所有的，
you have the statistical models that they can learn from data,
你有可以从数据中学习的统计模型，
but they cannot actually establish the causal relationship between the input and outputs.
但它们不能实际建立输入和输出之间的因果关系。
The best type of models that we could have is physical models,
我们可以拥有的最好的模型类型是物理模型，
that describes the exact dynamics of a process
它描述了一个过程的确切动态，
than you have basically a causal models,
而不是因果模型，
and in the middle, you have a kind of a spectrum of different types of causal models,
在中间，你可以看到一系列不同类型的因果模型，
so one thing that we realize is,
所以我们意识到的一件事是，
basically liquid neural networks are something that is called dynamic causal models,
液态神经网络是一种被称为动态因果模型的东西，
dynamic causal models are models that can adapt their dynamics to,
动态因果模型是能够使其动态适应的模型，
so that they can extract the, the, the essence of a task
这样他们就可以提取一个任务的本质，
and, and really find out the, the, the, the relationship of an input output relationship of a task,
并真正找出一个任务的输入输出关系，
based on a mechanism that is ruled out by this differential equation here.
基于一个被这里的微分方程排除的机制。
So it has parameters A B and C,
所以，它有参数 A B 和 C ，
that they account for internal interventions to the system,
它们解释了对系统的内部干预，
that if I change something in the middle of the system,
如果我在系统中间改变了一些东西，
there mechanism that can control that processes,
那里有一个机制，可以控制那个过程，
if if something that comes from outside and intervention inside the process of the system,
如果某个东西来自系统的外部，干预系统的内部，
then you would actually get into,
那么你实际上会进入，
you can, you can control those kind of processes with the dynamic causal model.
你可以用动态因果模型来控制那种过程。
Now, a little bit,
现在，有一点，
I wanted to go through the causal modeling process of neural network,
我想要讲一下神经网络的因果模型过程，
basically a differential equation can form a causal structure,
基本上，一个微分方程式就可以形成一个因果结构，
what, what does that mean,
这是什么意思，
that means it can predict from the current situation,
这意味着它可以从目前的情况预测，
we can predict the future one, one step in the future of a process,
我们可以预测一个过程的未来一步，
that temporal causation.
那个时间的因果关系。
And another thing is that,
另一件事是，
if I change something or intervene in a system,
如果我改变了一些东西或干预了一个系统，
how can I, can I actually control that intervention,
我如何能够真正控制那个干预，
so or, or can I account for that intervention that I had in the system,
或者我能解释我在这个系统中的干预，
so this would construct this two points,
所以这就构成了这两个点，
being able to account for future evolution of a system and interventions,
能够说明未来制度的演变和干预，
and being able to account for interventions in the system.
以及能够解释系统中的干预。
So if you have these two models,
所以，如果你有这两个模型，
then you have a causal structure.
那么你就有了一个因果结构。
So for that, I'm just skipping over over this part,
所以，我跳过这一部分，
I just wanted to tell you that,
我只是想告诉你，
I mean I wanted to show you like more about,
我的意思是，我想向你展示更多关于，
how you're driving this connection between liquid networks and causal models,
你是如何推动这种液态网络和因果模型之间的联系的，
but I share this slide,
但我分享这张幻灯片，
so you can see
为了让你们看到，
and also a professor tomorrow is going to give a lecture on the topic,
明天还有一位教授会讲授这个主题，
that hopefully she can cover these parts.
希望她能讲到这些部分。
And just a couple of remarks on, on, on the performance of the network
还有几个关于网络的性能，
and what's the implication of having a causal model.
以及拥有因果模型的含义。
Now, let's look at this environment,
现在，让我们来看看这个环境，
we trained some neural networks,
我们训练了一些神经网络，
these neural networks are basically learned to fly towards a target in an unstructured environment,
这些神经网络是学习在非结构化环境中飞向目标的，
so we collected some data,
所以我们收集了一些数据，
we trained neural networks instances,
我们训练了神经网络实例，
and then we tested this,
然后我们测试了这个，
then then we take this neural networks that we train
然后我们得到了我们训练的神经网络，
by moving towards, like basically these are scenes that are drone is inside the forest
就像这些场景是无人机在森林里，
and the drone is navigating towards a target, okay.
无人机正在向目标导航。
Now, we collect this data from a couple of traces that we simulate,
好的，现在我们从模拟的几条轨迹中收集数据，
then we take this data,
然后我们获取这些数据，
we train neural networks,
我们训练神经网络，
we bring the neural networks back on the drone
我们把神经网络带回无人机上，
and we test them on the drone,
我们在无人机上对它们进行测试，
to see, to see whether they can learn to navigate this task
看看自己能否学会导航这个任务，
without even programming what is the objective of the task,
连编程任务的目的是什么都不用，
basically, the objective of the task has to be distilled from the data itself,
基本上，任务的目标必须从数据本身中提取出来，
and as we saw here on the right,
正如我们在右边看到的，
we see the decision making process of these networks,
我们看到了这些网络的决策过程，
that liquid networks learned to pay attention to the target,
液态神经网络学习专注于目标，
as the target becomes visible,
当目标变得可见时，
that means it actually figured out the most important part of this process
这意味着它实际上意识到这个过程中最重要的部分，
was really focusing on the target,
真正专注于目标，
even if there is an unstructured kind of kind of input data to the system,
即使存在一种系统的非结构化输入，
now if we compare the attention map of this neural circuit policies,
现在，如果我们比较这个神经回路策略的注意图，
which is the first, the second column compared to the other attention maps,
这是第二列与其他注意图相比，
we see that, the only network type of network that learn from this data
我们看到，唯一从这个数据中学习的网络
to pay attention to this target is liquid neural networks,
关注这个目标的是液态神经网络，
and that's the kind of implication that you have,
这就是你所拥有的那种暗示，
so you learn the cause and effect of a task using a liquid neural network,
所以，你可以使用液态神经网络来了解任务的因果关系，
that has dramatically less number of parameters compared to other types of neural networks.
与其他类型的神经网络相比，它的参数数量要少得多。
Now, as I told you,
现在，就像我告诉你的，
the relation between two neurons,
两个神经元之间的关系，
can be defined by a differential equation by neuron equation and synapse equation,
可以用一个由神经元方程和突触方程定义的微分方程来定义，
we recently have solved this differential equation, also in closed-form,
我们最近解了这个微分方程，也是封闭形式的，
and then this gave rise to a new type of neural networks,
然后这就产生了一种新型的神经网络，
which is again a close-form,
它也是一种封闭的形式，
continuous time neural networks, you call them CFC,
连续时间的神经网络，你叫它们 CFC ，
these are the close form liquid networks,
这些是封闭形式的液态网络，
they have the same behavior,
它们有相同的行为，
but they are basically defining close-form.
但它们定义的封闭形式。
Now, what does that mean,
那么，这意味着什么，
that means if I have a differential equation,
这意味着，如果我有一个微分方程，
you see the ODE on the top,
你可以看到最上面的 ODE ，
if I simulate this ODE, okay,
如果我模拟这个 ODE ，
the close-form solution would actually give you the very same behavior of the differential equation itself,
闭合形式的解会给出和微分方程本身非常相同的行为，
but it does not require any numerical solvers,
但它不需要任何数值解算器，
so it does not require any kind of, you know, complex numerical solvers,
所以它不需要任何形式的复杂的数值解算器，
so as a result, you could scale liquid neural networks much larger to much larger instances,
所以，你可以将液态神经网络扩展到更大的实例，
if you want to scale the networks in terms of performance in modeling dynamics.
如果你想在建模动态方面提高网络的性能。
Liquid neural networks, we see here a series of different types of advanced recurrent networks
液态神经网络，我们在这里看到了一系列不同类型的高级递归网络，
and we see variants of close-form liquid neural networks and LTC themselves,
我们看到了闭合形式液态神经网络的变体和 LTC 本身，
that are performing remarkably better than the other systems in modeling physical dynamics.
它们在模拟物理动态方面的表现明显好于其他系统。
And the last thing I want to show is
我想要说明的最后一件事是，
the difference between this understanding causality and understanding the cause and effect of a task
理解因果关系和理解一个任务的因果关系
and not being able to understand that.
和不能理解它之间的区别。
Now here you see a drone,
现在你看到的是一架无人机，
which is an agent that wants to navigate towards a target,
它是一个想要导航到目标的[中介]，
there's a target in the environment,
环境中有一个目标，
now we collected traces of a drone navigating towards this target in this forest,
现在我们收集了一架无人机在这片森林中朝这个目标航行的痕迹，
then what we did, we collected this data,
然后我们收集这些数据，
then we train neural networks,
然后训练神经网络，
and now we brought back this neural networks on the drone
现在我们把无人机上的神经网络带回来，
to see whether they learned to navigate towards that target or not.
看看它们是否学会了向目标导航。
Now here I'm showing the performance of an LSTM neural network,
现在，我将展示一个 LSTM 神经网络的性能，
so, as we see,
所以，正如我们看到的，
the LSTM is basically completely like looking around
LSTM 基本上完全是东张西望，
and it cannot really control the drone,
不能真正控制无人机，
actually, if you look at the attention map of the system
如果你看一下系统的注意力地图，
actually looks all around the the place,
实际上可以看到整个地方，
it did not really realize what's the objective of the task from data,
它没有真正从数据中意识到任务的目标，
so it could not really associate anything
所以它不能真正联系任何东西，
or learn something meaningful from the data.
也不能从数据中学到有意义的东西。
And then here is in liquid neural network on the same task,
然后这里是在液态神经网络上的相同任务，
look at the attention map here,
请看这里的注意力图，
as the drone is going towards that target,
因为无人机正在向那个目标移动，
and that's the kind of flexibility,
这是一种灵活性，
that you can learn the actual cause and effect of a task from neural networks.
你可以从神经网络中了解任务的实际原因和结果。
Now, okay, so I'm going to conclude now,
现在，好的，我现在要结束了，
I showed you these plots,
我给你看了这些情节，
I showed you that there is overparameterization regime
我向你展示了有过度的参数化机制，
and we have an idea about what kind of benefits you would get in that regime,
我们有一个你可以在这个机制中获得好处的想法，
and what kind of intuitive understand, theoretical understanding do we have for neural networks,
我们对神经网络有什么样直观理解，理论理解，
and then I showed you that there are neural networks like liquid neural networks,
然后我向你展示了像液态神经网络这样的神经网络，
that have inductive biases from brains,
它有来自大脑的归纳偏见，
that can actually resolve a couple of problems,
可以解决一些问题，
for example, the robustness while being significantly smaller than overparamize networks,
例如，稳健性，它比超参数网络要小得多，
so it is not that you always have to dramatically overparamize neural networks,
所以，并不是说你必须总是戏剧性地过度参数化神经网络，
but you can have inductive biases to actually gain good performance.
你可以有归纳偏差来获得良好的性能。
To sum up,
总结一下，
the law of robustness is real,
健壮性法则是真实存在的，
so that's something that is came out of a theory is number of parameters,
所以这是一个理论得出的东西是参数的数量，
it's, it's necessarily has to be large if you want to have with effective dimensionality,
它必须很大，如果你想要有有效的维度，
so one of the ideas that we have,
所以我们有一个想法，
I'll talk about effective dimensionality here,
我将在这里谈论有效维度，
the overparamatization definitely improves generalization and robustness,
过度参数化无疑提高了泛化和健壮性，
but it has some sociotechnical challenges,
但它存在一些社会技术挑战，
so inductive biases or architectural [],
所以，归纳偏见或[]架构，
why do we have different types of architectures
为什么我们有不同类型的架构，
and why studying the brain is actually a good thing
为什么研究大脑是一件好事，
is because we can actually get smarter in design neural networks
因为我们可以在设计神经网络时变得更聪明，
and not just blindly overparameters overparamizing them,
而不仅仅是盲目地超参数化，
so we can really put incorporating some of some ideas to really get what's going on
所以我们可以把一些想法结合起来，真正了解正在发生的事情，
and liquid neural networks, they can enable robust representation learning outside of overparamization regime,
液态神经网络，它们可以在过度参数化的机制之外实现健壮的表示学习，
because of their cause of mechanisms,
因为它们的原因机制，
they reduce networks [],
它们减少了网络的[]，
so that's speculation that I have,
所以这是我的猜测，
I have to, we have to actually think about the theoretical implication here,
我们必须真正思考这里的理论含义，
but I, what I think is that,
但我认为，
the reason why liquid neural networks can pass or break the, the universal law of robustness,
液态神经网络之所以能够通过或打破网络健壮性这一普遍规律，
is because they can extract a better or more minimum kind of effective dimensionality out of data,
是因为它们可以从数据中提取出更好或更小的有效维度，
so you have datasets,
所以你有数据集，
so if the, if the effective dimensionality get reduced by a paramitized neural network,
如果有效维度被一个参数化的神经网络降低了，
then the law robust still holds, okay,
那么这个定律仍然成立。
given the number of data.
考虑到数据的数量。
And that's the end of my presentation,
我的演讲到此结束，
I'm just putting here at the end a couple of resources,
我在这里最后放了几个资源，
if you want to get hands on with liquid neural networks,
如果你想接触到液态神经网络，
we have put together like really good documentations
我们已经整理了非常好的文档，
and I think you would enjoy to play around with these systems for your own applications.
我想你会喜欢把这些系统用于你自己的应用程序。
Thank you for your attention.
谢谢大家的关注。